<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Madelyn Oliveri</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Madelyn Oliveri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Mess with the Python</title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/09/pythonblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/09/pythonblog/</guid>
      <description>Recently in class, we have been using Python to explore essential packages and functions that assist in the ease of data manipulation. My personal favorite has been Reguar Expression operations. RegEx helps to learn how to match, search, and transform a string. Let&#39;s look at a few examples!
Wait wait wait. We&#39;ve already encountered our first problem. How can I show you Python coding if I&#39;m using R to build this website?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Blog</title>
      <link>/pythonblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pythonblog/</guid>
      <description>Although I&#39;ve struggled quite a bit with program language used for coding due to its complexity, I find comfort in knowing I have the ability to fact-check data or even create my own datasets for research.
Recently in class, we have been using Python to explore essential packages such as numpy and pandas. Numpy is a Python library helpful for working with arrays. In particular, we worked</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/project1.knit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1.knit/</guid>
      <description>In this study I will be comparing motor vehicle data alongside U.S civilian house fire data; in-particular, examining trends in the number of deaths over the years from each type of accident, with the common variable being the year (1960-2018). Motor vehicle accident data was collected from the Bureau of Transportation Statistics which includes motorcycles while excluding commercial vehicles. It includes the number of crashes, the total number of deaths (presented as Deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/project1.utf8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1.utf8/</guid>
      <description>In this study I will be comparing motor vehicle data alongside U.S civilian house fire data; in-particular, examining trends in the number of deaths over the years from each type of accident, with the common variable being the year (1960-2018). Motor vehicle accident data was collected from the Bureau of Transportation Statistics which includes motorcycles while excluding commercial vehicles. It includes the number of crashes, the total number of deaths (presented as Deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>This dataset of 75 observations contains information to study any potential correlations or predictors of relationships between salary, educational background degree type, etc. There are many factors that influence salaries and degrees obtained such as experience, opportunity, family operations, business owner status, future goals, etc., but comparisons between this smaller set of variables may provide some type of trend and clarity on the relationships. The variables are as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>  Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
